<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>Overview</title>
    </properties>
    
    <head>
        <meta name="description" content="BST Player provides a consistent API to add
        Windows Media Player, QuickTime, VLC Media Player, DivX Web Player, Flash plugins and HTML 5 video
        to GWT applications. It also feature a module to embed YouTube videos and classes to
        facilitate custom player controls" />
    </head>
    <body>
        <section name="Overview">
            <div id="ohloh">
                <script type="text/javascript"
                src="http://www.ohloh.net/p/315620/widgets/project_thin_badge.js">
                </script>
            </div>
            <p>
                The API makes Windows Media Player, QuickTime player, Adobe &#174; Flash&#174; player, VLC Media Player,
                DivX&#174; Web Player plugins, HTML 5 video elements and YouTube videos available in
                GWT applications like other GWT widgets.
            </p>
            <p>
                The API feature sets of classes and interfaces that presents a consistent means of
                interacting with the supported player plugins.  Knowing how to use one
                player widget means you are well at home with other player widgets.
            </p>
            <p>
                Each player widget exposes methods to load media files, initiate playback,
                pause, stop, change playback position and volume.  General media plugin events
                such as loading progress, playback started, playback finished, IO errors are also
                supported via event handlers
            </p>
            <p>
                The API also feature plugin detection, which is central to the smooth operation of
                the library as well as classes to facilitate the development of custom HTML-based player
                controls (skins).  The custom players can be used like a cross-browser media
                player in GWT applications. Exceptions are thrown in the absence of a required plugin,
                hence allowing you to display an alternative message (or widget).
            </p>
            <p>
                Read the <a href="getting-started.html">Getting Started</a> guide for the general
                usage of the API.
            </p>

            <subsection name="Demo">
                <p>
                    The
                    <a href="demo/showcase/index.html">BST Player Showcase</a> application showcase
                    the various features of the API.
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Questions">
                <p>
                    Post all questions on the
                    <a href="http://groups.google.com/group/bst-player">bst-player</a>
                    group, hopefully someone will try to provide answers as best as possible.
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="Suggestions and Issues">
                <p>
                    Suggestions and feedbacks are always welcome as regards improving the project.
                    You may post your suggestions and all issues on the
                    <a href="http://code.google.com/p/bst-player/issues/">Issues page</a>.
                </p>
                <p>Happy coding ...</p>
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>