<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<document xmlns="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
  xsi:schemaLocation="http://maven.apache.org/XDOC/2.0 http://maven.apache.org/xsd/xdoc-2.0.xsd">

    <properties>
        <title>Migration Guide</title>
    </properties>
    
    <head>
        <meta name="description" content="Migrate from previous BST Player releases in simple steps" />
    </head>
    <body>
        <section name="Migrating to version 1.3">
            <p>
                Version 1.3 introduced many enhancements to the API and is backwards compatible.
            </p>

            <subsection name="GWT 2.2 dependency">
                <p>
                    The library now depends on GWT 2.2 or later.
                </p>
            </subsection>
        </section>

        <section name="Migrating to version 1.2">
            <p>
                Version 1.2 introduce many enhancements that may affect existing code.  The
                effect may not be much but it is worth taking note of.
            </p>

            <subsection name="GWT 2.x dependency">
                <p>
                    The library now requires GWT 2.0 or later.  GWT has come a long way since version 1.6 so
                    this may not be an issue, as most GWT projects are based on 2.x already.
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="WinMediaPlayer and non-IE browsers">
                <p>
                    <code>WinMediaPlayer</code> widget now requires the Windows Media Player plugin for
                    Firefox in non-IE browsers to guarantee programmable control.  Since this may not
                    always be required, two operating modes are defined - the embed-only and
                    programmable modes.
                </p>
                <p>
                    In embed-only mode, the widget is expected to be used for rendering only without
                    any programmatic control.  Consequently method calls on the widget in this mode
                    may fail and such errors/failures are suppressed.
                </p>
                <p>
                    In programmable mode - the default, the widget throws <code>PluginNotFoundException</code>
                    in non-IE browsers without the Windows Media Player plugin for Firefox.
                </p>
            </subsection>

        </section>

        <section name="Migrating from version 0.6">
            <p>
                The following improvements on version 0.6 may require minor tweaks to existing code.
                Such changes however, should only take a few minutes to rectify.
            </p>

            <subsection name="Code Refactoring">
                <p>
                    The library is now split into different modules consisting of:
                </p>
                    
                <ul>
                    <li>
                        <b>com.bramosystems.oss.player.core.Core</b> -
                        The core classes of the API (including the base player widgets)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>com.bramosystems.oss.player.core.event.Event</b> -
                        The new event classes (inherited by the Core module)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>com.bramosystems.oss.player.capsule.Capsule</b> -
                        The sample custom sound player (inherits the Core module)
                    </li>
                    <li>
                        <b>com.bramosystems.oss.player.flat.FlatVideoPlayer</b> -
                        The sample custom video player (inherits the Core module)
                    </li>
                </ul>
                    
                <p>
                    Consequently, existing codes that inherits the
                    <code>com.bramosystems.gwt.player.BSTPlayer</code> module will now need to inherit:
                </p>
                <p>
                    <code>com.bramosystems.oss.player.core.Core</code> - if using only the base player
                    widgets (such as WinMediaPlayer, QuickTimePlayer etc)
                </p>
                <p>
                    <code>com.bramosystems.oss.player.capsule.Capsule</code> - if using the sample
                    custom sound player
                </p>
                <p>
                    <code>com.bramosystems.oss.player.flat.FlatVideoPlayer</code> - if using the sample
                    custom video player
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="New Event Handlers">
                <p>
                    GWT 1.6 introduced a new EventHandler system which makes the development of complex,
                    decoupled applications easier. Inline with this, the <code>MediaStateListener</code>
                    class has been replaced with the following handlers in the
                    <code>com.bramosystems.oss.player.core.event.client</code> package:
                </p>

                <table>
                    <tr>
                        <td>PlayerStateHandler</td>
                        <td>handles events that are fired when the state of the player changes</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>PlayStateHandler</td>
                        <td>handles events that are fired when the state of media playback changes</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>MediaInfoHandler</td>
                        <td>handles MediaInfoEvent fired whenever media metadata is available</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>LoadingProgressHandler</td>
                        <td>handles events that are fired when the progress of a loading media changes</td>
                    </tr>
                    <tr>
                        <td>DebugHandler</td>
                        <td>handles events that are fired when info/error level messages are generated by the embedded plugin</td>
                    </tr>
                </table>

                <p>
                    Also, <code>VolumeChangeListener</code> used for volume control is replaced with
                    <code>VolumeChangeHandler</code>, while <code>SeekChangeListener</code> used for
                    seek controls is replaced with <code>SeekChangeHandler</code>.
                </p>
                <p>
                    Existing codes that use:
                </p>


                <source>
player.addMediaStateListener{ new MediaStateListener() {
...
}};</source>
                
                <p>
                    will now need to do:
                </p>

                <source>
player.addPlayerStateHandler { new PlayerStateHandler() {
    // if interested in player state changes
}};
player.addPlayStateHandler { new PlayStateHandler() {
    // if interested in play state changes
}};

etc...     </source>

                <p>
                    Please check the
                    <a href="bst-player-api/apidocs/index.html">API</a> for details.
                </p>
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="New FlashMediaPlayer">
                The <code>FlashMP3Player</code> and <code>FlashVideoPlayer</code> widgets has been removed
                in favour of <code>FlashMediaPlayer</code> widget.  The new widget is designed to handle
                all media types supported by the Adobe Flash player including MP3 sound, FLV video
                and MP4 sound/video.
            </subsection>

            <subsection name="New CustomPlayerControl widget">
                The <code>FlatCustomControl</code> widget has been replaced with the new
                <code>CustomPlayerControl</code> widget. The widget provides a simple player UI
                with play/pause/stop buttons as well as a seekbar to control the supported media plugins.
            </subsection>
        </section>
    </body>
</document>